

Raluca Gui

Im Kirschenwäldchen 26 • 60437 Frankfurt am Main • Tel: +49 (176) 998-43452 • Email:raluca.gui@gmail.com

Summary

I am an experienced statistician, with a BA in Mathematics, an MA in Economics and Quantitative Methods and a PhD in Marketing and Social Networks. I am proficient in using different statistical softwares such as R, Stata and Python. I have been teaching Statistics,

Quantitative Methods and Machine Leaning for more than 5 years. I have been working in a cross-cultural environment for more than 10 years. I speak fluently English, French and Romanian, and I have two children.

Experience

European Central Bank

Frankfurt, Germany June 2019 - Present

Data Science Analyst - DG-HR

Responsibilities in:

- Application development for organisational planning and data exploration
- Dashboard design and development (in Tableau and R Shiny) and reporting related to strategic HR KPIs
- Predictive analytics and projections
- R training and coaching for HR Analytics colleagues

European Central Bank

Frankfurt, Germany October 2018 - June 2019

Data Science PhD Trainee - DG-Statistics Responsibilities in:

- Identification of potential use cases for automation of processes in data collection
- Proof of concept development for the classification of financial institutions

University of Zurich

Zurich, Switzerland

May 2013 - October 2018

Research Associate

Responsibilities in:

- Research in Marketing with a focus on social networks
- Teaching Master level courses in Marketing Analytics and Machine Learning.

Universidad Carlos III de Madrid

Madrid, Spain

Teaching Associate

Sep 2009 - Sep 2012

Teaching undergraduate level courses in Statistics I and II, Marketing and Operations Management

IBM Global Financing

Budapest, Hungary

Business Support Operations Specialist

Aug 2006 - Aug 2007

Manage lease portfolio, settlement, end of lease decisions; reporting and audit support activities.

Central European University (CEU) - Labor Project

Budapest, Hungary

Research Assistant

June 2005 - Sep 2005

The CEU Labor Project conducts academic and policy-relevant research on labor markets and other applied microeconomic issues in Central and Eastern Europe. My responsibilities as RA were in statistical analysis (using Stata) of large employer-employee matched datasets, as well as in data mining and data cleaning.

Laboratoire Logiciels Systemes et Reseaux (LSR-IMAG)

Grenoble, France

Research Assistant

June 2003 - Sep 2003

The LSR -IMAG Laboratory research contributes to the progress in technologies for the development of large scale software systems. Such systems are characterised by very large software sizes, large teams working on them, large amount of data manipulated, and a highly distributed nature. As part of the team, I was assigned to develop in JAVA an analyser and evaluator of algebraic expressions for evaluating equations and constraints for the 2nd version of AROM - an object oriented database system.

Education

University of Zurich
PhD in Marketing
PhD in Marketing
PhD in Marketing
PhD in Marketing
Feb 2014 - March 2021

Universidad Carlos III de Madrid
MADRID, Spain
MA in Quantitative Methods
Major: Marketing and Statistics

Central European University

Budapest, Hungary

MA in EconomicsSep 2004 - June 2006Babes - Bolyai UniversityCLUJ-NAPOCA, ROMANIABA in MathematicsSep 2000 - June 2004

Skills

Technical specialties: R, Python, Stata, Matlab, SPSS; Tableau; LaTeX, Keynote, PowerPoint.

Languages: Romanian (mother tongue), English (fluent), French (fluent), Spanish (intermediate), German (intermediate), Bulgarian (basic).